汉化：@大月半子（PPm）
https://weibo.com/baba
是的。
Yes.
你失败了。
You failed.
我没有。
I didn't.
枪在我手里。
The gun is in my hand.
我以为我拿到了。
I thought I had it.
对不起，父亲。下次我会做到的。
Sorry, Father. I'll make it next time.
永远不要把任何事情视为理所当然。
Never take anything for granted.
上帝会把它拿走的。
God will take it from you.
上帝是坏的?
Is God bad?
上帝是公平的。
God is fair.
你差点就抓到我了，对吧，小子?
You almost got me, didn't you, boy?
我的白发是从你那儿遗传来的
Did I get my white hair from you
还是从妈妈？
or from Mom?
从你的妈妈。
From your mother.
真不敢相信我们居然没有她的照片。
I can't believe we don't have any pictures of her.
一切都被大火烧毁了。
Everything was destroyed in the fire.
你知道的。
You know that.
我只能救你。
I could only save you.
她漂亮吗?
Was she beautiful?
她很聪明。
She was smart.
就像你。
Like you.
我得到了多少?
How many did I get?
全部。
All of them.
所以我今天要进城，对吧?
So I get to go to town today, right?
你的生存失败了。
You failed survival.
已经三个月了。
It's been three months.
而且，我刚给你剪了个超赞的发型。
Plus, I just gave you a killer haircut.
相信我。
Trust me.
你得先通过所有的测试。
You need to pass all your tests first.
好吧，除了平常
All right, apart from the usual,
我订了五种蕨类植物，
I have an order of five ferns,
两种榕树，
two ficuses,
还有一种巨柱蕨。
and the Columnea grandiosa.
凤尾兰。
Gloriosa.
我今天要去凤凰城吗?
Am I taking Phoenix today?
不是今天。
Not today.
已经有一段时间了。
It's been a while.
我说了，不。
I said, no.
你要么松开皮带，
You either loosen up that leash,
要么迟早她会咬掉的。
or sooner or later, she's gonna bite it off.
和埃尔南德斯一起去。
Go with Hernandez.
日落前回来！
Back by sunset!
我会的。
I will.
嘿,埃尔南德斯。
Hey, Hernandez.
嘿，真漂亮。
Hey, gorgeous.
♬飞吧，鸟♬
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♬穿越浩荡的大海♬
♪ All across the mighty sea ♪
♬唱吧，女孩♬
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♪为我唱出你小小的心♪
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
真漂亮。
That's beautiful.
你瞎编的?
You made that up?
我记得是我妈在我小时候唱给我听的。
I think my mom sang it to me when I was little.
我只记得第一部分。
That first part's all I remember.
你想去看她吗?
You wanna pay her a visit?
-但我父亲不想让我……-你不说我也不说。
- But my father doesn't want me... - I won't tell if you don't.
♬飞吧，鸟♬
♪ Fly, bird ♪
警方已经对托马斯·汉尼曼医生发出全州警报，
Police have issued a statewide alert for Dr. Thomas Hanniman,
据信他在底特律地区经营一个
who's believed to be running an organ trafficking ring
-器官贩运团伙。 -谢谢。
- in the Detroit area. - Thank you.
绑架事件数量惊人
The alarming number of abductions
最近在这个城市里上升了。
has recently risen in the city.
这是一个不断发展的故事。我们会通知你
This is a developing story. We'll update you
随着更多的信息曝光。
as more information comes to light.
现在让我们看一下周末的天气预报。
Now let's take a look at the weekend forecast.
大家早上好。我是气象学家杰里……
Good morning, everyone. I'm meteorologist Jerry...
各位，拉。帮帮我。
Everyone, pull. Help me.
卡住了。
It's stuck.
嘿，想试试吗?
Hey, wanna try something?
好吧。
Okay.
动手吧。
Do it.
再快点，再快点。
Faster, faster.
我头晕。
I'm getting dizzy.
嘿，伙计们。进来吧。晚餐。
Hey, guys. Come on in. Dinner.
但我不想进去。
But I don't wanna go inside.
来吧,伙计们!
Come on, guys!
“圣约庇护所。”
"Covenant Shelter."
和你赛跑。
Race you.
嘿,等等!
Hey, wait up!
-玩得开心吗? -嗯哼。
- You having fun? - Mm-hm.
好了，我们走吧。
All right, let's go.
我要尿尿。
I need to pee.
好吧，快点。
Okay, well, be quick.
我不想惹你父亲生气。
I don't wanna anger your father.
♬飞吧，鸟♬
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♬穿越浩荡的大海♬
♪ All across the mighty sea ♪
♬唱吧，女孩♬
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♬为我唱出你小小的心♬
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
哇,你很漂亮。
Wow, you're pretty.
你叫什么名字，美女?
What's your name, gorgeous?
我叫雷兰。
Mine's Raylan.
我不关心。
I don't care.
我得走了。我父亲在等我。
I need to go. My father's waiting for me.
我打个响指
I snap my fingers
它就会咬掉你的蛋蛋。
and he'll bite your testicles off.
哇。
Wow.
好吧。
Okay.
如果吓到你了，我很抱歉。
Well, I'm sorry if I scared you.
谁说的?
Who said you did?
回头见。
I'll see you around.
来吧，影子。
Come on, Shadow.
你没事吧?
You okay?
是的。
Yes.
只是个怪人。
Just a weirdo.
是的。
Yeah.
这附近不缺这种东西。
No shortage of those around here.
跟着他们。
Follow them.
谢谢，埃尔南德斯。
Thanks, Hernandez.
我们今天玩得很开心。
We had a lot of fun today.
如果你不介意的话，我下周再带她去。
I'll take her again next week if you're okay with it.
不。
No.
今天就足够了。
Today was enough.
-这不关我的事，但是… -你说得对。
- It's none of my business, but... - You're right.
不关我事。
It's not.
你是个坏人。
You're a bad man.
一个做过坏事的人。
A man who's done terrible things.
至少我知道你是这么想的。
At least, I know you think that.
就像我有时对自己做的那样。
Just like sometimes I do about myself.
战争改变了我们所有人。
War changes us all.
没有灵魂能从那里回归圣洁。
No soul returns holy from it.
别让她为此付出代价。
Don't make her pay for that.
谢谢。
Thanks.
你介意把车开到路边吗?
You mind moving your vehicle off the road, please?
这是……
This is...
这是回城的唯一道路。
This is the only road back to town.
你服过役?
You served?
是的。
Yeah.
我们也一样。
We all did too.
-伊拉克? -是的。
- Iraq? - Yeah.
不光彩地从一场不光彩的战争中退伍。
Dishonorably discharged from a dishonorable war.
我想说这让我们很光荣。你不会吗？
I'd say that makes us honorable somehow. Wouldn't you?
不。
No.
你能把你的卡车挪开吗?
Can you move your truck off the road now?
当然,宝贝。
Sure, baby.
你要什么都行。
Whatever you want.
下个月的课。
Lessons next month.
好吧。
Okay.
我明年想去上学。
I wanna go to school next year.
-这是学校……-一所真正的学校，
- This is school... - A real school,
和其他像我一样的孩子。
with other kids like me.
在家上学更安全。
Homeschool is safer.
我不想要安全。
I don't wanna be safe.
我想做个正常人。我想有朋友。
I wanna be normal. I wanna have friends.
-我想过… -够了!
- I wanna live a... - Enough!
够了。
Enough.
我已经失去过一个女儿。
I already lost a daughter once.
我不会失去你的。
I'm not losing you.
但是我孤独。
But I'm lonely.
你根本不知道孤独是什么感觉。
You have no idea what it is to be alone.
你有我。
You have me.
有你还不够。
You're not enough.
“圣约人庇护所。
"Covenant Shelter.
你的新家在等着你呢。”
Your new home awaits you."
影子?
Shadow?
影子。
Shadow.
哦，上帝。
Oh, God.
盒子！快点！
The box! Now!
走吧!
Go!
去找那个女孩。
Go get the girl.
开门。
Open the door.
打开!
Open up!
他妈的什么?
What the fuck?
哦!
Oh!
坚持住，兄弟。
Hang on, brother.
张开你的下颚。
Open your jaw.
别动。
Stay still.
呼吸,兄弟。
Breathe, brother.
那家伙是海豹突击队员。
The guy's a Navy SEAL.
该死的海豹突击队员死了，兄弟。
Fucking dead SEAL, bro.
最好离开那里，孩子。
Better get out of there, kid.
他和你在下面!
He's down there with you!
该死的瞎子在下面!
Blind fuck is down there!
给雷兰打电话。
Call Raylan.
金属盒子几乎装满了水。
Metal box is almost full of water.
你宁愿看到孩子活着…
You prefer to see the kid alive...
你到这里来。
you come in here.
你以为我在耍你吗?
You think I'm fucking with you?
不。
No.
有根带电的电线快到水里了。
There's a live wire about to reach the water.
出来，不然她就完蛋了!
Come out, or she's fried!
聪明的混蛋。
Clever fuck.
没有枪,嗯?
No guns, huh?
没问题。
No problem.
你很坚强。
You're tough.
但你完了。
But you're done.
他妈的什么?
What the fuck?
哟,兄弟。
Yo, bro.
呼吸。
Breathe.
来吧,呼吸。
Come on, breathe.
呼吸。
Breathe.
是那个老瞎子干的吗?
The old blind man did this?
啊哈。
Uh-huh.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
我可以走。
I can walk.
我说了，我能走。
I said, I can walk.
发生了什么事？
What's happening?
盖上出口。
Cover the exits.
他妈的什么?
What the fuck?
他们还在下面。
They're still down here.
发生什么事情了?
What's happening?
-他们是谁? -我不知道。
- Who are they? - I don't know.
你不用害怕，小女孩。
You don't need to be afraid, little girl.
这一切只是一个大误会。
This has all just been one big misunderstanding.
你要害怕的不是我…
It's not me you need to be scared of...
但站在你旁边的人。
but the man standing next to you.
我不知道他是谁。
Now, I don't know who he is.
但我知道他不是谁。
But I know who he's not.
我该告诉她还是你?
Should I tell her or you?
干掉他,兄弟。
Finish him, bro.
不!
No!
-爸爸!爸爸,醒醒。-你不是很了不起吗？
- Dad! Dad, wake up. - Aren't you something?
放开我!
Let me go!
来吧。
Come on.
不，没事的。
No, it's okay.
对，就是这样。
Yeah, there you go.
那就这样吧。
There you go.
你真的不记得我了，是吗?
You really don't remember me, do you?
也许这个会有帮助。
Maybe this will help.
看到了吗?
See?
什么……?
What...?
几年前，我们家发生了一场火灾。
Years ago, there was a fire in our house.
警察指责我。
Cops blamed me.
我在监狱里待了八年。
I spent eight years in prison,
不知道还能不能再见到你。
wondering if I'd ever see you again.
我甚至不知道你是死是活。
I didn't even know if you were dead or alive.
这个变态一定……
This creep here must have...
找到了你，把你留给了他自己。
found you and kept you for himself.
下面是本地新闻
Up next in local news,
今早底特律西部的一个冰毒实验室着火了。
a meth lab caught fire in west Detroit this morning.
警方逮捕了主要嫌疑人。
Police were able to arrest the primary suspect.
该男子已被拘留，可能因过去几年中
The man was taken into custody and could face charges
犯下的大量罪行
for a large number of crimes committed
-而面临指控。-你不知道
- over the past several years. - You have no idea
我是多么期待这一刻。
how much I've been waiting for this moment.
他伤害你了吗?
Did he hurt you?
但他确实把你从我身边偷走了，
But he did steal you away from me,
现在他必须死，你明白吗?
and now he must die, you understand?
杀了他。
Kill him.
-不。-你他妈在干什么?
- No. - Fuck are you doing?
别在我孩子面前。去外面做。
Not in front of my kid. Do it outside.
醒醒吧，你个混蛋。
Wake up, you blind fuck.
哦!他妈的!
Oh! Fuck!
该死的懦夫。
Fucking coward.
带她上车，我去找这混蛋。
Take her to the truck while I hunt this motherfucker.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
-放开我! -你怎么了?
- Let me go! - What's wrong with you?
你他妈的想回家吗?
Fucking wanna go home?
我不管你是谁。
I don't care who you are.
我他妈要教训教训你。
I'm gonna teach you some fucking manners, yo.
你这个忘恩负义的小贱人。
You ungrateful, little bitch.
不。
No.
住手。
Stop.
拜托!
Please!
住手!
Stop!
走。走，走。
Move. Go, go.
走。快点。
Move. Now.
快走!
Move!
对不起，伙计。
I'm sorry, man.
-他回屋里了。 -我知道。
- He's back in the house. - I know.
他想让我们跟着他。
He wants us to follow him.
这些愚蠢的游戏玩够了。
Enough of these silly games.
这是他的夹克。
It's his jacket.
好样的。
Attaboy.
等等。
Wait.
站住。
Stop.
是真的吗?
Is it true?
走。
Move.
我的真名是什么?
What's my real name?
马上过来!
Get over here now!
我的生日是什么时候?
When's my birthday?
-我真正的那个? -住口!
- My real one? - Stop it!
不，你住口!
No, you stop it!
走!
Go!
嘿。
Hey.
凤凰!
Phoenix!
冷静下来,女孩。
Calm down, girl.
冷静下来。
Calm down.
别动。
Stay.
把她放进卡车里。
Put her in the truck.
哇，哇，哇，哇。
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
-你的狗在里面。 -狗死了。
- Your dog's in there. - Dog's dead.
你又不知道。
You don't know that.
你想去看看吗?
You wanna go and find out?
不!
No!
早上好,公主。
Good morning, princess.
你感觉如何?
How you feeling?
你还好吧?
You all right?
想和我一起坐吗?
Wanna sit with me?
来，和我一起坐。来吧。
Come, sit with me. Come on.
是的。
Yeah.
那就这样吧。
There you go.
是的。
Yeah.
门是开着的。
Door's open.
不再是囚犯了。
Not a prisoner anymore.
你是说，我可以走了?
You mean, I can go?
如果你想。
If you want.
或者你可以留在这里
Or you can stay here
找出你的真实身份。
and find out who you really are.
我有兄弟姐妹吗?
Do I have any brothers or sisters?
不幸的是，没有。
Unfortunately, no.
我的生日是什么时候?
When's my birthday?
2月20日。
February 20th.
我妈妈叫什么名字?
What was my mother's name?
约瑟芬。
Josephine.
我长得象她吗?
Do I look like her?
是的。
Yeah.
你象。
You do.
塔拉。
Tara.
那是你的真名。
That's your real name.
塔拉。
Tara.
那人告诉你的一切都是谎言。
Everything that man told you is a lie.
他怎么了?
What happened to him?
他罪有应得。
He got what he deserved.
嘿。我不后悔。
Hey. I'm not sorry.
你也不应该。
You shouldn't be either.
我想去。
I wanna go.
哪里?你要去哪里?
Where? Where you gonna go?
我知道有个避难所。
There's a shelter I know.
就像我说的,
Like I said,
你不再是囚犯了。
you're not a prisoner anymore.
♬飞吧，鸟♬
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♬穿过♬
♪ Out across the ♪
♬茫茫大海♬
♪ Great wide sea ♪
♬唱吧，女孩♬
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♬为我唱出你小小的心♬
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
♬飞吧，鸟♬
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♬飞越巍峨的悬崖♬
♪ Fly across the mighty cliffs ♪
♬睡吧，女孩♬
♪ Sleep, girl ♪
♬妈妈会给你一个晚安吻♬
♪ Mama's gonna give you A good-night kiss ♪
妈妈?
Mom?
就像我说的…
Like I said...
他告诉你的一切都是谎言。
everything he told you was a lie.
我的泰拉?
My Tara?
你……
You...
长得太大了，呵呵。
got so big, heh.
我能抱抱你吗?
Can I hug you?
过来。
Come here.
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
嗯。哦,上帝。
Mmm. Oh, God.
哦，宝贝，我们好想你。
Oh, baby, we missed you so much.
嗯…
Mmm...
你看看。
There you are.
你是一个多么漂亮的孩子。
You were such a beautiful baby.
把它弄出来。
Get it out.
把它弄出来。来吧。
Get it out. Come on.
好了。好了。好了。
There you go. There you go. There you go.
-对不起。-没什么好道歉的。
- Sorry. - Nothing to apologize for.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
就是那场毁了我们家的大火……
The same fire that destroyed our family...
它烧坏了我的内部。
it burned up my insides.
妈妈和爸爸曾经有一个…
Mom and Dad used to have a...
厨房，呵……
kitchen, heh...
在我们房子的地下室，
in the basement of our house,
我们过去常在那里做饭。
where we used to cook.
是为了我们的生意。
It was for our business.
你渴吗?
Are you thirsty?
泰拉?
Tara?
我要死了。
I'm dying.
什么?
What?
化学物质产生的烟雾…
The smoke from the chemicals...
毒死了我的血液，严重损坏了我的心脏。
poisoned my blood and badly damaged my heart.
我想我没有多少时间了。
I don't think I have much time left.
你能做点什么吗?
Is there anything you can do?
我听说你在我们的老房子里给我留了花。
I heard you left flowers for me at our old house.
是真的吗?
Is that true?
哦。
Oh.
你不是希望
Weren't you wishing
你妈妈很健康还活着?
your mama was healthy and alive?
是的。
Yes.
我需要一个新的心脏，宝贝。
I need a new heart, baby.
但不是一般的心脏。
But not just any heart.
医生说一定是…
Doctor said it has to be a, uh...
那一定是…
It must be a...
兼容的捐献者。
compatible donor.
就像直系亲属一样。
Like a direct relative.
你拥有能救你妈妈一命的天赋。
You hold the gift that can save your mama's life.
宝贝，我需要这份礼物。
And, baby, I need that gift.
我们最终会像一个人一样在一起。
We'll finally be together as one.
你会活在我身上。
You'll live on in me.
回家。
Go home.
离开。
Go away.
我说了，走吧。
I said, go.
留下来。
Stay.
回家。
Go home.
我希望你能理解
I hope you understand
这个手术的高风险。
the high risks of this procedure.
我想我给你的钱够多了。
I think I pay you enough.
闭嘴，做好你的工作。
Shut up and do your job.
为什么她还活着?
Why is she still alive?
如果她死了，她的心脏也死了。
If she's dead, so is her heart.
而且我没法保持足够的新鲜感
And I can't keep it fresh long enough
没有合适的设备。
without the proper equipment.
我得在她还活着的时候把它取出来。
I have to cut it out of her while she's still breathing.
嘿。
Hey.
嘿,嘿,嘿。
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿,嘿。
Hey, hey.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你怎么了，伙计?
What's wrong with you, man?
他们在里面做的事是不对的。
What they're doing in there is wrong.
她是我们的厨师。
She's our cook.
如果她死了，就没有产品了。
If she dies, there's no product.
如果没有产品，就没有我们。
If there's no product, there's no us.
明白？
¿Comprende?
还是他妈的错了。
Still fucking wrong.
嘿。
Hey.
-你准备好了吗? -嗯哼。
- You ready? - Mm-hm.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
他妈的什么?
What the fuck?
去看看吧。
Go check it out.
嗯。
Hm.
你杀了我兄弟!
You killed my brother!
你这瞎眼怪物!
You blind freak!
我要把你的脑袋像南瓜一样切开，伙计。
I'm gonna carve your fucking head open like a pumpkin, man.
这是为了影子。
This is for Shadow.
哦,他妈的。
Oh, fuck.
不!
No!
是他。
It's him.
他是怎么找到……？
How the hell did he find...?
不忠的该死的动物。
Disloyal fucking animal.
一切都好吗?
Is everything okay?
是的,一切都好。
Yeah, everything's okay.
-没事的，我保证。-宝贝，我该担心吗?
- Everything's okay, I promise. - Baby, should I be worried?
不，不。一点也不。
No, no. Not at all.
我抓到你了。我抓到你了。
I got you. I got you.
没有电我不能工作。
I can't work without power.
嗯…
Uh...
那么，计划有变。
Change of plans, then.
收拾你的东西。带上女孩。
Pack your things. Bring the girl.
劳尔。
Raul.
带上男人。杀了那个瞎子。
Bring the men. Kill the blind man.
-我们多少人? -你们所有人!
- How many of us? - All of you!
我们走吧。
Let's go.
他们会杀了她。
They're gonna kill her.
这对我来说很不好。
And that's not cool with me.
他们要走了。
They're leaving now.
你身后的梯子
The ladder behind you
直接指向他们。
leads directly to them.
你最好快点。
You'd better hurry.
向左走。
Go left.
那边。
That way.
他会把你们都杀了。
He'll kill you all.
他妈的。我出去。
Fuck it. I'm out.
嘿,嘿!嘿!
Hey, hey! Hey!
早上好,草泥马。
Good morning, motherfucker.
-宝贝。 -嘘,嘘。没关系。
- Baby. - Shh, shh. It's okay.
住手。
Stop it.
宝贝?
Baby?
有人吗?
Hello?
我看不见你。
I can't see you.
宝贝?
Baby?
我在这里!你在哪里?
I'm over here! Where are you?
宝贝?
Baby?
我抓住你了，混蛋。
I got you, motherfucker.
不。
No.
不!不!
No! No!
不。
No.
不!
No!
凤凰!
Phoenix!
现在…
Now...
你会看到
you're gonna see
我所看到的。
what I see.
凤凰?
Phoenix?
住手。
Stop.
哦，住手!
Oh, stop!
你……
You...
你不能靠近我。
You mustn't come near me.
他说的一切……
Everything he said...
是真的。
is true.
我不是父亲。
I am no father.
我杀了。
I have killed.
我…
I...
强奸了。
have raped.
我…
I...
什么都不是。
am nothing.
什么都不是……
Nothing...
只是一个怪物。
but a monster.
而你……
And you...
不能在我身边。
cannot be around me.
永远。
Ever.
所以走吧。
So go.
快点。走。
Now. Go.
走吧!
Go!
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
泰拉?
Tara?
不。
No.
不。不。
No. No.
拜托。
Please.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
我来帮你。
Let me help you.
我能救你。
I can save you.
你已经救了。
You already have.
嘿。
Hey.
还能再坐一个人吗?
Think there's room for one more?
我肯定还有地儿。
I'm sure there is.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
我的名字叫凤凰。
My name is Phoenix.
汉化：@大月半子（PPm）
https://weibo.com/baba